<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#hi-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-hi/act/hrs/237-2.5"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-hi/act/hrs/237-2.5"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#hi-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-hi"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-hi/act/hrs/237-2.5/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-hi/act/hrs/237-2.5/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#hi-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-hi/act/hrs/237-2.5/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-hi/act/hrs/237-2.5/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="hi-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-hi/legislature" showAs="Hawaii Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_237">
        <num>Chapter 237</num>
        <heading>General Excise Tax Law</heading>
        <section eId="sec_237_2_5">
          <num>237-2.5</num>
          <heading>Section 237-2.5</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§237-2  &quot;Business&quot;, &quot;engaging&quot;
in business, defined.
As used in this chapter:
&quot;Business&quot; includes all activities
(personal, professional, or corporate) engaged in or caused to be engaged in
with the object of gain or economic benefit either direct or indirect, but does
not include casual sales.
&quot;Engaging&quot;, with reference to engaging
or continuing in business, includes the exercise of corporate or franchise
powers. [L 1935, c 141, pt of §1; RL 1945, §5443; RL 1955, §117-2; HRS §237-2;
am L 2017, c 12, §49]
Attorney General Opinions
Agreement of sale executed by a partnership dealing in land
was not a &quot;casual sale&quot;.  Att. Gen. Op. 62-1.
Co-op apartment corporation operating and managing apartment
building is engaged in business and is taxable on its receipts of monthly &quot;maintenance&quot;
charges from stockholder-lessees.  Att. Gen. Op. 62-47.
Application of excise tax to activities in foreign trade
zone.  Att. Gen. Op. 64-52.
Hawaii's general excise tax and use tax are not expressly
preempted by the federal Foreign-Trade Zones Act of 1934, and Congress has not
assumed exclusive regulatory powers in foreign-trade zones such that the State
is preempted from imposing taxes on all activity within a foreign-trade zone. 
Ultimately, whether a state tax can be applied to a particular activity within
a foreign-trade zone depends on whether the tax conflicts with the purposes and
objectives of the federal Act.  Att. Gen. Op. 21-01.
Case Notes
&quot;Casual sale&quot; does not exclude unusual sales within
taxpayer's business.  40 H. 722 (1955).
Attorney's activities as trustee, executor and corporate
director were not so isolated or unconnected as to constitute &quot;casual&quot;
transactions.  53 H. 435, 496 P.2d 1 (1972).
Engaging in activity with &quot;object of gain or economic
benefit&quot; construed.  53 H. 435, 496 P.2d 1 (1972).
Out-of-state company's continuing leasing of telecast rights
performable only in Hawaii is &quot;business&quot; within this section,
although agreement consummated outside of Hawaii.  57 H. 175, 554 P.2d 242
(1976).
Nondomiciliary corporation investing capital in Hawaiian land
held to be &quot;engaging in business.&quot;  57 H. 436, 559 P.2d 264 (1977).
Taxability of transactions between joint venture and its
member.  59 H. 307, 582 P.2d 703 (1978).
Where taxpayer gained or economically benefited from
subleasing transactions, the director's assessment and imposition of the
general excise tax for taxpayer's subleasing activities was proper.  110 H. 25,
129 P.3d 528 (2006).
Taxpayer partnership's provision of medical equipment and
ancillary services to its joint venture constituted &quot;business&quot; under
this section and was thus made subject to the general excise tax by §237-20. 
93 H. 267 (App.), 999 P.2d 865 (2000).
Cited:  48 H. 486, 490, 405 P.2d 382 (1965).
Previous
Vol04_Ch0201-0257
Next</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
