<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#hi-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-hi/act/hrs/240-1"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-hi/act/hrs/240-1"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#hi-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-hi"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-hi/act/hrs/240-1/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-hi/act/hrs/240-1/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#hi-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-hi/act/hrs/240-1/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-hi/act/hrs/240-1/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="hi-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-hi/legislature" showAs="Hawaii Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_240">
        <num>Chapter 240</num>
        <heading>Rental Motor Vehicle, Tour Vehicle, and Car-Sharing Vehicle Surcharge Tax</heading>
        <section eId="sec_240_1">
          <num>240-1</num>
          <heading>Electric light and power companies, tax on</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§240-1  Electric light and power companies,
tax on.
Every person operating in the State an electric light or power
business as a public utility, whose franchise does not provide for the payment
to the county in which the public utility operates of a tax, or a tax of less
than two and one-half per cent, based upon the gross receipts of such person
from all electric light or power furnished to consumers during each calendar
year, shall file with the director of finance of the county in which the public
utility operates, within one month after the expiration of each calendar year,
a detailed statement showing all gross receipts from all electric light or
power furnished to consumers during the preceding calendar year.  Such person
shall, at the same time pay to the director of finance, for and on behalf of such
county, in addition to any and all other payments required to be made by law,
two and one-half per cent of the gross receipts; or, if such person's franchise
provides for a tax of less than two and one-half per cent of the gross
proceeds, the difference between the tax required under such franchise and two
and one-half per cent of the gross receipts, of such person from all electric
light or power furnished to consumers during the preceding calendar year. [L
1937, c 105, pt of §1; RL 1945, pt of §5681; RL 1955, §131-1; HRS §240-1; am L
1982, c 167, §1]
Previous
Vol04_Ch0201-0257
Next</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
