<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#hi-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-hi/act/hrs/349-8"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-hi/act/hrs/349-8"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#hi-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-hi"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-hi/act/hrs/349-8/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-hi/act/hrs/349-8/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#hi-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-hi/act/hrs/349-8/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-hi/act/hrs/349-8/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="hi-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-hi/legislature" showAs="Hawaii Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_349">
        <num>Chapter 349</num>
        <heading>Child Care</heading>
        <section eId="sec_349_8">
          <num>349-8</num>
          <heading>Section 349-8</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§349-8  Powers of other departments and
agencies; cooperation with the executive office on aging.
It shall be the
duty and responsibility of every state department and county agency providing
programs and services to the aging, in actively working toward the goals and
objectives articulated in the state comprehensive master plan for elders, to
coordinate with the executive office on aging the development of its program
plans and clear its final plans with the office prior to implementation of such
plans.  The executive heads of all such departments and agencies shall
cooperate with the executive office on aging in providing information as the
office deems necessary for the effective discharge of its duties under sections
349-3, 349-5, 349-6, and 349-7.  However, nothing contained in this chapter
shall be deemed to delegate or detract in any way from the functions, powers,
and duties prescribed by law for any other department or agency of this State,
nor to interrupt or preclude the direct relationships of any such department or
agency or units of county government in the performance of such functions, powers,
and duties.  Each department, agency, officer, and employee of the State and of
the counties shall cooperate and assist the executive office on aging in the
performance of the function, powers, and duties of the office. [L 1976, c 217,
pt of §2; am L 1990, c 67, §8]
Previous
Vol07_Ch0346-0398
Next</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
