<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#hi-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-hi/act/hrs/353-71"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-hi/act/hrs/353-71"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#hi-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-hi"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-hi/act/hrs/353-71/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-hi/act/hrs/353-71/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#hi-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-hi/act/hrs/353-71/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-hi/act/hrs/353-71/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="hi-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-hi/legislature" showAs="Hawaii Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_353">
        <num>Chapter 353</num>
        <heading>Corrections</heading>
        <section eId="sec_353_71">
          <num>353-71</num>
          <heading>Section 353-71</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§353-71  Parole officer and assistant parole
officers.
The Hawaii paroling authority may appoint and remove at pleasure
a parole officer and assistant parole officers as may be necessary, who shall
receive such compensation as shall be provided by law.  The duties of the
parole officer shall be as follows:
(1)  To keep a record of all paroled prisoners; to add
from time to time thereafter information concerning the employment and wages of
each paroled prisoner, together with the name of the paroled prisoner's
employer and such details concerning the paroled prisoner's health, conduct,
and environment as may come to the attention of the parole officer either from
reports made to the parole officer or through the parole officer's own personal
investigation;
(2)  To receive reports from paroled prisoners as may
be required by the rules and regulations of the paroling authority and to check
such reports by personal investigations and by conferences with the employers
of such prisoners and such other persons as can give information concerning the
habits, work, and environment of such prisoners;
(3)  To investigate and keep informed upon the habits,
work, wages, and environment of such prisoners, if any there be, as are not
required to report to the parole officer;
(4)  To make such other investigations, secure such
other information and data, perform such other duties and make such other
reports, in addition to those which may be required by law, as may be required
by the paroling authority;
(5)  To make a report once in each month to the
paroling authority, together with such additional reports as the circumstances
call for, concerning the prisoners on parole and their conduct and environment;
and
(6)  As far as practicable, to assist in obtaining
suitable employment for paroled prisoners and otherwise assist in
rehabilitation of such paroled prisoners.
Each assistant parole officer shall have such
of the powers and duties of the parole officer hereinabove provided for as
shall be prescribed by the paroling authority. [L 1931, c 126, §8; RL 1935,
§6459; am L 1939, c 203, pt of §6; RL 1945, §3964; RL 1955, §83-69; HRS
§353-71; am L 1976, c 92, pt of §8; gen ch 1985]
Previous
Vol07_Ch0346-0398
Next</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
