<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#hi-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-hi/act/hrs/363-3.5"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-hi/act/hrs/363-3.5"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#hi-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-hi"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-hi/act/hrs/363-3.5/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-hi/act/hrs/363-3.5/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#hi-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-hi/act/hrs/363-3.5/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-hi/act/hrs/363-3.5/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="hi-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-hi/legislature" showAs="Hawaii Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_363">
        <num>Chapter 363</num>
        <heading>Hawaiian Home Lands Trust</heading>
        <section eId="sec_363_3_5">
          <num>363-3.5</num>
          <heading>Section 363-3.5</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§363-3  Activities of the office.
Except as otherwise provided by law, the office shall:
(1)  Maintain or cause to be maintained, subject to
the control and supervision of the office, a center to which veterans,
including their families and dependents, may come for information, counsel,
aid, and assistance, and by which they may be directed or referred to any
agency in the community whose function it is, by law or otherwise, to provide
the services, assistance, or benefits which in each instance appear necessary
or appropriate.  Agencies to which any referrals may be made shall include, but
are not limited to, departments and divisions of the federal and state
governments, veterans' organizations, and so-called &quot;private&quot; social
agencies;
(2)  Assume the initiative, in cooperation with
agencies in the community, for coordinating all services now available, and
which hereafter may become available, for the use and benefit of veterans,
including their families and dependents, to the end that maximum effectiveness
of the services may be realized, and overlapping and duplication of effort as
between agencies may be minimized;
(3)  Assemble, analyze, compile, and disseminate
factual, up-to-date information with respect to:
(A)
Benefits, rights,
and services of whatever nature to which veterans, including their families and
dependents, are entitled, or which may be available to them; and
(B)  The structure, functions, area of
service, and other pertinent information regarding each agency and organization
participating in the veterans' assistance program in the State;
(4)  Cooperate with federal departments and other
agencies which, by law, have responsibility for the administration of rights
and benefits granted by the federal government to veterans, including their
families and dependents;
(5)  As soon as possible after the close of each
fiscal year, compile and submit to the governor, for such use or distribution
as the governor may deem appropriate, a comprehensive report of the activities
and operations of the office, and of all disbursements and expenditures
authorized by the office under this section;
(6)  Inspect every three years all state war memorials
and veterans' cemeteries for repair and maintenance deficiencies, and report
all repair and maintenance problems at these memorials and cemeteries to the
adjutant general, the comptroller, and the legislature prior to the start of
the next regular session; and
(7)  Organize, coordinate, and conduct a biennial Hawaii
veterans summit.  The summit shall assemble any department or division of the
federal or state government, veterans' organizations, or any other entity in
the community whose function is, by law or otherwise, to provide services,
assistance, or benefits to assist veterans and their families and dependents,
to discuss and collaborate on issues affecting veterans and their families and
dependents.  The issues to be addressed shall include benefits, rights, and
services available to veterans, and any other pertinent information on
assistance for veterans and their families and dependents. [L 1951, c 75, §6;
RL 1955, §349-6; am L Sp 1959 2d, c 1, §20; HRS §363-3; am L 1970, c 105, §5;
gen ch 1985; am L 1987, c 339, §4; am L 1988, c 115, §5; am L 1995, c 63, §2;
am L 1997, c 360, §1; am L 2018, c 52, §1]
Previous
Vol07_Ch0346-0398
Next</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
